Guide to the Jeff Feldmann photograph collection ARCH169
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Jeff Feldmann photograph collection
1980 - 2017, undated
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Feldmann, Jeff
ARCH169
1 Linear Feet (4 containers)
The Jeff Feldmann Photograph Collection consists primarily of photographs of the University of Hartford campus and sporting events. The collection also includes other university related photographs, correspondence, and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Most of the photographs in the collection have been digitized and are acecssible with a university username and password at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:78.
Biographical / Historical
Jeff Feldmann worked at the University of Hartford as a foreman on the grounds department for twenty-eight years. Feldmann enjoys photography, particularly capturing landscapes and sporting events. During his time at the University, he photographed the campus and university events, primarily university athletics. Over the years many of his photographs have been on display in university buildings and used in university publications. While students were on breaks, he would also take photographs for the Informer.
Feldmann has been awarded Connecticut's Girls and Women in Sports photo contest three times (1992, 2002, and 2003). He has had exhibitions at the Noah Webster Library and Clinton Library. The State Library has his photograph of the 1991 Tax Rally on permanent display. His work has also been included in juried shows at the Essex River Museum, Wintonbury Art League, and ETC Gallery.
Feldmann was the President of the University of Hartford Staff Association from 1982-1983. On April 17, 1999, Feldmann was awarded the A. Peter LoMaglio Award during the 9th Annual Alumni Athletic Hall of Fame ceremony. Feldmann retired in September 2004.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of photographs taken by Jeff Feldmann of the University of Hartford campus and its athletic programs. University events like commencements, move-in day, and the Special Olympics are also included in the collection. The collection also includes correspondence and memorabilia that Feldmann collected while working at the University. Much of his correspondence is with University Presidents Stephen Joel Trachtenberg and Walter Harrison. Among his memorabilia are several autographed items from University athletes and alumni.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: I. Photographs and II. Correspondence and Memorabilia.
Photographs; Correspondence; University of Hartford -- Sports; University of Hartford -- Alumni and Alumnae; College athletes; University of Hartford; Trachtenberg, Stephen Joel
- Photographs, 1987-2017, undated; I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs taken by Jeff Feldmann of the University of Hartford and its events. These photographs include prints, negatives, slides, and images on Compact Discs (CDs).
  Arrangement
  The Photographs series is arranged into four subseries: a) Campus and Events Prints and Negatives, b) Athletic Prints and Negatives, c) Slides, and d) Compact Discs (CDs).
  - Campus and Event Prints and Negatives, 1987-2016, undated; a
    - Auerbach, 2003 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Bates House, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bates House, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Bridge Summer, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Bridge Fall, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1, Box 1)
    - Bridge Winter, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1, Box 1)
    - Bridge Spring, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Photos, 2001 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Photos, 2006 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Winter, 2003 - 2004 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Spring, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Fall, 2004 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Commencement, 2002 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Commencement, 2003 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Commencement, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Concessions Stand, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Freshman Arrival, 2003 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Harry Jack Gray Center, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Konover, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Main Campus Sign, 1987 - 1988, 2003 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Pedestrian Bridge, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Sports Center, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Sports Fields, 2001 - 2002 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Trachtenberg, Harrison, and Tonkin, 2016 Fall (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Village, 2001 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
  - Athletic Prints and Negatives, 1989-2014, undated; b
    - American East Champion, 2001 - 2002 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Campus Mascot, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - First Game New Gym, 1989 - 1990 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Feldmann, 2014 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Greater Hartford Open, 2002 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hartford Golf Team Picture, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - G.W Game, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hartford Baseball, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hartford Civic Center, 1993 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hartford VS BU, 2011 May 27 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hartford North Eastern, 1991 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hart Marathon Game, 2001 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Hawks VS New Hampshire, 1991 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Jack Ayer, 1992 - 1993 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Jeff Bagwell, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Jen Rizzotti, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Jerry Kelly Photos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Maine VS Hartford, 1997 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Maura Rogers, 1992 - 1993 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Men's Basket Ball, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Men's Basket Ball Team photo, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Mike Bond, 1992 - 1993 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Mohegan Sun, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Non UofH Photos, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vermont Conference Game, 1991 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vin Baker Day, Cerca 1990 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vin Baker, 1992 - 1993 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vin Baker Celtics, Undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vin Baker Civic Center, 1989 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
    - Vin Baker Golf, 2000 Jul 31 (Box Shared Photograph Box 1)
  - Slides, 1999-2004, undated; c
    - Campus Photos, 1999 - 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Graduation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Memorial, 2002 Sep 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Outdoor Classroom, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - UofH After the Blizzard of 1996, 1997 Jan (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - UofH Campus Flooding, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - UofH Ward, 2002 Jun (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - UofH Winter, 2001, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Compact Discs (CDs), 2004-2017; d
    - Special Olympics, 2004 (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - UNotes, 2004-2007 (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - Women's Basketball, 2006 Apr (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - Volleyball Tournament, 2007 Apr (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - Presidents' Panel, Fall 2016 (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - Baseball - Hawks vs. Bobcats, first game at Dunkin' Donuts Park, 2017 Apr 11 (Box Shared CD Box 3)
- Correspondence and Memorabilia, 1980-2017; II
  This series contains correspondence and memorabilia that Feldmann saved while working at the University of Hartford. The majority of the correspondence is from University of Hartford President Stephen Joel Trachtenberg. There are also a note and cards from President Walter Harrison and a note from university alumnus and professional golfer Jerry Kelly. The memorabilia includes both items pertaining to the University and its athletes. Most noteworthy are autographed items from Madame Jihan Sadat, Jeff Bagwell, Vin Baker, Jerry Kelly, Jen Rizzotti, and the 2002 Women's Basketball team. Autographed photographs are in the Photograph Series.
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1992, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sports Memorabilia, 1992 Nov 23, 1992-2017 (Box 1, Folder 17-18, Box 0207303175195)
  - University of Hartford Memorabilia, 1982-1987, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)